# **ESMA ERDEM**

Bangor, ME | 207-412-8936 | esmaerdem94@gmail.com | <u>Linkedin.com/in/esma-erdem-398723229/</u> | <u>github.com/EsmaNErdem</u> | esmanerdem.github.io/esmaPorfolio/

#### SUMMARY

Highly motivated Software Engineer with entry-level experience in software development, Python and Javascript. Equipped with proven problem-solving and analytical thinking skills gained through Astronautical Engineering with High Honors Degree and a track record of success in team leadership and effective communication in my previous role as a sales manager. Excited to combine my technical skills and business acumen to drive impactful results and grow with the company.

#### **SKILLS**

Web Development, JavaScript, DOM Manipulation, Event Driven Programming, Git/Terminal/Github, Modern JavaScript and Testing, AJAX, jQuery, ReactJS, Redux, SQL, PostgreSQL, Flask, Node, Express, Data Structures and Algorithms

### **PROJECTS**

## Wicked Acadia [ wicked-acadia.onrender.com/ ]

Apr. 2023 - May 2023

- Created to help nature enthusiasts plan trips to Acadia National Park.
- Built with Python, Flask, JavaScript, SQLAlchhemy-Postgres, and Jinja templates.
- Implemented user-friendly features like sign-up, login, and favorites/bookmarks functionality.
- Developed extensive documentation and unit tests for functionality and maintainability.
- GitHub Repo: github.com/EsmaNErdem/capstone1

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

Springboard | Online | July, 2023 Software Engineering Certification

Turkish Aeronautical Association University | Ankara, Turkiye | July, 2017

BS Astronautical Engineering, 3.29

- Relevant Coursework: Algorithmic Computer Programming, Linear Algebra, Computational Methods
- Acquired advanced algorithmic and computational skills through rigorous coursework and an immersive internship experience. Self-taught Matlab and expertly applied these skills to successfully complete internship projects and subsequent coursework.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Student, Springboard Software Engineering | Remote

Jan 2023 - Current

- Completed 800-hour course that covered key aspects of front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms. Included 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of in-depth portfolio projects.
- Honed skills in Web Development, JavaScript, DOM Manipulation, Event Driven Programming, Git/Terminal/Github, Modern JavaScript and Testing, AJAX, jQuery, ReactJS, Redux, SQL, PostgreSQL, Flask, Node, Express, Data Structures, and Algorithms

Sales Manager, Cool As A Moose | Provincetown, MA

Jan. 2019 - Sept. 2022

- Managed successful retail/gift shop, overseeing operations, and leading a team. Achieved 70% revenue growth in the
  first year through effective customer service and strategic planning.
- Conducted regular health checks on the point-of-sale system and analyzed inventory data using retail star software.
- Developed and executed successful marketing campaigns, increasing brand visibility and community engagement. Coached and trained new hires across multiple locations on operations, customer service, and leadership.